?Are you ready, kids
准备好了吗，孩子们
:KIDS
!Aye, aye, Captain
:儿童
！是啊是啊，队长
.I can't hear you
.我听不到你说话
:KIDS
!Aye, aye, Captain
:儿童
！是啊是啊，队长
♪ !Ooh
♪ ！哦
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
?under the sea ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
?在海底♪
♪ !Spongebob Squarepants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
♪  Spongebob
!Squarepants♪
♪ 海绵宝宝
！方裤♪
♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
♪ 如果是航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
♪ !Spongebob Squarepants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
♪ ?Spongebob Squarepants!♪ready
♪ ？海绵宝宝！♪ 准备好了
♪ !Spongebob Squarepants
♪ !海绵宝宝
[hearty laughter ]
[爽朗的笑声]
[flute playing ]
[长笛演奏]
Captioning sponsored by THE]
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
字幕由 THE 赞助]
美国教育部
[and NICKELODEON
[和尼克罗迪恩
[bell ringing ]
[铃声响起]
:MRS. PUFF
.Okay, class, quiet, quiet
：太太。泡芙
.好了，上课，安静，安静
Now, get out your
pencils and paper
现在，拿出你的
铅笔和纸
and write down
.the assignment
并写下
.作业
[class groans ]
[班级呻吟声]
?Did you hear that
？你听到了吗
.We get an assignment
.我们接到一个任务
Everyone must write an essay
on what notto do
每个人都必须写一篇作文
关于不该做什么
.at a stoplight
.在红绿灯处
[all groaning ]
[全都呻吟]
?Did you hear that
？你听到了吗
What not to do
!at a stoplight
不该做什么
！在红绿灯处
!In no less than 800 words
！不少于800字
[squeal of delight ]
[喜悦的尖叫声]
[all groaning ]
[全都呻吟]
?Did you hear that
!?800 words
？你听到了吗
!?800字
!Yeah, I know
！是的，我知道
.Due tomorrow
.明天到期
:And remember, class
.work hard and no goofing off
：记住，同学们
.努力工作，不偷懒
:SPONGEBOB
!Okay, Gary, no goofing off
:海绵宝宝
！好吧，加里，别偷懒了
I am about to write
the greatest essay
我正要写
最伟大的论文
.of all time
.有史以来
,Like most great essays
it will be written
,就像大多数伟大的文章一样
它将被写成
.on paper
.纸上
Even more important
...than the paper is
更重要的是
...比纸
.the pencil
.铅笔
[bell dings ]
[铃声]
A pencil is sharp or as dull
.as I like
铅笔是锋利的还是钝的
.如我所愿
,Hmm, funny, as my ideas grow
.you shrink
，嗯，有趣，随着我的想法的增长
.你缩小了
[chuckles ]
[笑声]
Well, I couldn't have asked
好吧，我不能问
for a more beautiful day
.to write an essay
为了更美好的一天
.写一篇文章
[birds chirping ]
[鸟鸣声]
.Okay, here we go
.好的，我们开始吧
What Not To Do"
".At A Stoplight
什么不该做”
“.在红绿灯处
.Hey, this is easy
.嘿，这很容易
".By SpongeBob Squarepants"
“.海绵宝宝”
.Ha! This essay is pure gold
。哈！这篇文章是纯金的
,And now, pencil
get ready to do your stuff
，现在，铅笔
准备好做你的事情
.because herewe go
.因为我们走了
[ticking ]
[滴答作响]
...Gee
...哎呀
.this is harder than I thought
.这比我想象的要难
[ children laughing ]
[孩子们笑]
!Come on, SpongeBob
！来吧，海绵宝宝
It should be against the law
to have to write an essay
应该是违法的
必须写一篇论文
,on such a super sailorific
!sunshiny day
，在这样一个超级航海的
！阳光灿烂的日子
!Oh
！哦
,But I must press onward
,但我必须继续前进
because with this pencil and the
,completion of this essay
因为有了这支铅笔和
,完成本文
I'll be one step closer
!to my driver's license
我会更近一步
!到我的驾驶执照
[ tires squealing ]
[轮胎吱吱声]
.Oh, yeah
.哦，是的
.This'll be no problemo
.这不会有问题
.Why, I got plenty of time
.It's only 6:00
.为什么，我有足够的时间
.现在才6:00
[ ticking ]
[滴答作响]
.Okay... okay, here we go
.好吧...好吧，我们开始吧
.Here we go
。开始了
!Ahh
！啊啊
I know, I just need to get
我知道，我只需要得到
a little blood pumpin'
.in the old noodle
有点抽血
.在老面条里
?How about some calisthenics
?做一些健美操怎么样
!Hup-hoo! Hup-hoo
！呼呼！合虎
Ah, I can feel
!those juices pumpin' now
啊，我能感觉到
！那些果汁现在在泵动
[squeak ]
[吱吱]
[singsong squeaking ]
[吱吱作响的歌声]
[rhythmic squeaking ]
[有节奏的吱吱声]
[gurgling laughter ]
[咯咯笑声]
!?Hey! What am I doing
！？嘿！我在做什么
!I got to write that paper
！我必须写那篇论文
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
.Come on, pencil, make words
.来吧，铅笔，造字
[meow ]
[喵]
!Gary
！加里
Hey, hey, hey
嘿嘿嘿
?Gary, how's my favorite mollusk
？加里，我最喜欢的软体动物怎么样
How about
you let ol' SpongeBob
怎么样
你让海绵宝宝
fix you up
?something to eat
修理你
?吃点东西
[meows ]
[喵]
,What do you mean
?you're not hungry
,什么意思
？你不饿
[meows ]
[喵]
I know I have
!an essay to write
我知道我有
！要写一篇文章
!Now come on, Gary
！现在来吧，加里
[grunts ]
[咕哝]
I got to make sure
you get your nutrition
我必须确定
你得到你的营养
so I'm not leaving
.until you eat every single bite
所以我不会离开
.直到你吃完每一口
[loud chomp, gulp ]
[大声咀嚼，吞咽]
[burps ]
[打嗝]
[squishy slithering ]
[软软的滑行]
Gary, a-are you sure
you don't want
加里，你确定吗
你不想要
?some crème brulée
一些焦糖布丁
Or-or some chocoflavored
?algae bits
或者-或者一些巧克力味的
?藻类碎片
[squishes ]
[压扁]
.Gee, Gary sure made a mess
.哎呀，加里确实把事情弄得一团糟
I can't work on my essay
我无法完成我的论文
knowing there's a mess
.in the kitchen
知道事情很混乱
.在厨房里
[squeaking ]
[吱吱声]
...Hmm
...唔
I might as well clean
the rest of the floor
我不妨清洁一下
地板的其余部分
.while I'm at it
.当我在做的时候
[squeaking and whistling ]
[吱吱声和口哨声]
:[groaning ]
I should get
.these hard-to-reach places, too
：[呻吟]
我应该得到
.这些难以到达的地方也是如此
And these dishes
.need to be cleaned
还有这些菜
.需要清洁
.Can't have dirty garbage
.不能有脏垃圾
[clinking ]
[叮叮当当]
Well, I think
.it's clean enough now
嗯，我想
.现在够干净了
[bell tinkling ]
[铃声响起]
.Why, that didn't take too long
...It's only
.为什么，这并没有花太长时间
……这只是
!10:00
!Oh
！哦
.No more fooling around
.不再胡闹
.I got to get back to work
.我得回去工作了
Okay, Mr. Essay, I say
好吧，论文先生，我说
!prepare to be written
！准备写
[dive-bomber whooshing ]
[俯冲轰炸机的呼啸声]
[loud thud ]
[巨响]
!I'm doing it
！我正在做
!Yeah, yeah! Yeah
！是啊是啊！是的
...And some of these
...and some of these
...还有其中一些
...以及其中一些
...Almost there and
...快到了并且
.sizzling]...done ]
.铁板]...完成]
[sighs ]
[叹气]
Now let's see
.how it looks so far
现在让我们看看
.到目前为止看起来怎么样
"...The"
“...这”
!Break time
！休息时间
.Pacing always helps me think
.节奏总是帮助我思考
.Let's see, only 799 words to go
.让我们看看，只剩下 799 个字了
!Think, SpongeBob, think
！想一想，海绵宝宝，想一想
[snorting ]
[哼哼]
[loud ringing ]
[响亮的铃声]
:[gasping ]
!?W-Who's that
?Wha...? Hello
:[喘气]
！？那、那是谁
？什么...？你好
?Hey, Patrick, what you up to
？嘿，帕特里克，你在做什么
.Sleeping
。睡眠
.That's really fascinating
.这真是令人着迷
?Are you having a good sleep
？你睡得好吗
Any dreams you'd like
?to discuss
任何你想要的梦想
？讨论
...I remember on the
...我记得在
?SpongeBob
?海绵宝宝
You and I both know
that you're just using me
你我都知道
你只是在利用我
as a distraction
作为一种干扰
so you don't have to write
.your essay
所以你不必写
.你的论文
[gasping, stammering ]
[喘气，结巴]
!That is nottrue
！那不是真的
I called to have an engaging
.conversation with you
我打电话来是为了进行一次引人入胜的活动
.与你对话
.Well, I'm listening
.嗯，我在听
...Uh... Marco
...呃...马可
.Polo
。马球
[dial tone ]
[拨号音]
,Yeah, well
.I got to get going, Patrick
，是的，好吧
.我得走了，帕特里克
.Got an important essay to write
.有一篇重要的论文要写
.Sheesh, what a chatterbox
.Sheesh，真是个话匣子
?Can't he see that I'm busy
？他看不到我很忙吗
[chair squeaks ]
[椅子吱吱作响]
I can't write
with all these eraser shavings
我写不了
和所有这些橡皮屑
.all over my paper
.在我的纸上
[grunts ]
[咕哝]
Now they're floating
.around my thinking space
现在它们正在漂浮
.围绕我的思考空间
[inhales deeply ]
[深吸一口气]
.So long, pesky particles
.再见，讨厌的颗粒
[twittering squeaks ]
[叽叽喳喳的声音]
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
[choking ]
[窒息]
[gulps, gasps ]
[吞咽，喘气]
!I swallowed one
！我吞了一个
!I'm choking
！我窒息了
:[coughing ]
!Water
：[咳嗽]
！水
!Water
[frantic gulping ]
[疯狂地吞咽]
[gasping ]
[喘气]
.That was a close one
.那是一场亲密的比赛
[meows ]
[喵]
What do you mean
你是什​​么意思
,overly dramatic
?Gary
,过于戏剧化
？加里
All that choking
.sure made me hungry
一切令人窒息
.确实让我饿了
[meows ]
[喵]
I can't write on an
.empty stomach, Gary
我不能写在
.空腹，加里
.I got to have my brain food
.我得吃点健脑食品
...Now, let's see
?white or rye bread
...现在，让我们看看
？白面包或黑麦面包
?Or pumpernickel
？或粗麦粉
Gee, I guess it really depends
...on the meat inside
哎呀，我想这真的取决于
...里面的肉
.and the cheese
.还有奶酪
[doorbell rings ]
[门铃响了]
?A visitor
?一位访客
!?For me
！？为我
.Hello
。你好
Package for
.Mr. Squarepants
套餐适用于
.先生。方裤
!Great
！伟大的
!Thanks
！谢谢
So, uh, you like
?delivering mail
所以，呃，你喜欢
?递送邮件
.It puts bread on the table
.它把面包放在桌子上
?Rye or pumpernickel
?黑麦或粗麦黑麦
[obnoxious laughter ]
[令人讨厌的笑声]
.Oh, brother
.哦，兄弟
So, do you deliver
your own mail
那么，你交付吗
你自己的邮件
or do you have
?your own mailperson
或者你有
？你自己的邮递员
?But then who delivers hismail
？那么谁来投递他的邮件呢？
Is there a never-ending
chain of mailmen
有没有一个永无休止的
邮递员链
delivering mail
?to other mailmen
递送邮件
?给其他邮递员
Well, I guess a P.O. box
嗯，我猜是邮政信箱。盒子
,could, in theory
...break the chain
,理论上可以
...打破链条
Don't you have
?a paper to write
你没有吗
?要写的论文
[gulps ]
[咽口水]
How did he know I'm supposed
?to be writing an essay
他怎么知道我应该
?要写一篇论文
[blipping ]
[闪烁]
[slams ]
[大满贯]
In other news
在其他新闻中
local resident
SpongeBob Squarepants
当地居民
海绵宝宝
only has a few hours left
to complete his essay
只剩下几个小时了
完成他的论文
and yet he continues
.to goof off
但他仍然继续
. 偷懒
?When will he learn
？他什么时候才能学会
[screaming ]
[尖叫]
[glass breaking ]
[玻璃破碎]
[candle crackles ]
[蜡烛噼啪作响]
:[male voice ]
.Hey, SpongeBob
：[男声]
.嘿，海绵宝宝
.Over here
.在这里
.Come on, take a seat
.来吧，坐下
.Put your feet up and relax
.抬起双脚并放松
[bell chiming, gasping ]
[钟声响起，喘息]
!Oh, no
！哦，不
!Midnight
！午夜
[panting heavily ]
[气喘吁吁]
[alarms ringing ]
[警报响起]
!Must... get... back to desk
！必须……回到办公桌前
[yells ]
[大喊]
!Whew
！呼
.That was a close call
.那是一次千钧一发的机会
[screams ]
!My pants
[尖叫声]
！我的裤子
.Yoo-hoo
.Down here
.悠呼
.下面这里
!You get up here
！你站起来
!I got to get back to work
！我得回去工作了
!Freedom
！自由
!Stop, pants
！停下来，裤子
You get back here
...this instant
你回到这里
……这一刻
!pants
！裤子
[slams ]
[yells ]
[大满贯]
[大喊]
[groaning ]
[呻吟]
[clattering ]
[咔哒声]
.Time's... up... SpongeBob
.时间...到了...海绵宝宝
[gasps ]
[喘气]
!Burning
！燃烧
!Only 799 words to go
！只剩下 799 个字了
[sinister laughter ]
[阴险的笑声]
!No
！不
[screams ]
[尖叫声]
!?What have I done
！？我做了什么
!Help
！帮助
!Help, my house is on fire
！救命，我的房子着火了
[jabbering ]
[叽叽喳喳]
[brakes squeal ]
[刹车尖叫声]
!?SpongeBob, why
！？海绵宝宝，为什么
Why did you set me
?on fire, SpongeBob
你为何设置我
？着火了，海绵宝宝
Why didn't you just
!?write your essay
你为什么不直接
！？写你的论文
!Stop wasting time
！别再浪费时间了
[gasps ]
[喘气]
[pops ]
[流行音乐]
?Where's my essay
?我的论文在哪里
.Oh, there you are
.哦，你来了
[laughing ]
[笑]
.I must have dozed off
.我一定是打瞌睡了
?Let's see, where are we
？让我们看看，我们在哪里
?Do I dare look at the clock
？我敢看时钟吗
[creaking ]
[吱吱作响]
[ticking ]
[滴答作响]
:[gasping ]
!It's almost 9:00
:[喘气]
!Class starts in five minutes
！五分钟后开始上课
How am I going to write
this whole paper
我要怎么写
这整篇论文
!?in five minutes
！？五分钟后
How am I supposed to know
?what not to do at a stoplight
我怎么知道
？红绿灯时不该做什么
Feeding your snail
is something not to do
喂你的蜗牛
是不该做的事情
...at a stoplight
...在红绿灯处
and making a sandwich
and-and lighting candles
并制作三明治
和-和点燃蜡烛
and drinking water
and calling your friends
和饮用水
并打电话给你的朋友
and karate chopping the TV
和空手道砍电视
and shooting the breeze
with the mailman
和微风吹过
与邮递员
...and falling asleep and
...然后睡着了
[panting heavily ]
[气喘吁吁]
!Mrs. Puff
！太太。噗
!Mrs. Puff, I'm finished
！太太。噗，我说完了
!All 800 words
！全部800字
!I'm finished
!Here it is
！我完了
！就是这里
?They... Mrs. Puff
？他们...泡芙夫人
?Where is everybody
?大家都在哪里
,Oh, there you are
.SpongeBob
，哦，你来了
.海绵宝宝
,Here you go
.Mrs. Puff
,给你
.夫人。噗
800 words, all about stoplights
.and what not to do at them
800字，都是关于红绿灯的
.以及不该做什么
,I'm sorry, SpongeBob
.I tried to call you
，对不起，海绵宝宝
.我试着给你打电话
I have to go
.to a teachers' convention
我得走了
.参加教师大会
But what about
?my essay
但是呢
？我的论文
I decided to cancel
.the assignment
我决定取消
.作业
We're just going to take
a field trip
我们只是要采取
实地考察
.to a stoplight instead
.改为红绿灯
.See you next week
.下周见
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
[knocking ]
[敲门声]
[grunts ]
[咕哝]
!Whoo
！呼
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
[panting ]
[气喘吁吁]
.Oh, sweep, sweep
.哦，扫，扫
!Need... furniture
！需要...家具
[panting and gasping ]
[气喘吁吁]
Patrick, what's
?with the home improvement
帕特里克，什么是
?随着家居装修
[barks ]
[吠叫]
[panting ]
[气喘吁吁]
!Hey, Patrick
！嘿，帕特里克
!Ooh, sweep, sweep
哦，扫，扫
Well, Patrick, I came
over to see
好吧，帕特里克，我来了
过来看看
if you wanted to go
jelly fishing
如果你想去的话
果冻钓鱼
but I can see you're busy
.having an episode
但我看得出来你很忙
.有一个情节
,You know something
?Spongebob
,你知道一些事情
?海绵宝宝
it's just all fun and games
.for you
这只是乐趣和游戏
.为你
.Nothing really matters
.没有什么真正重要的
:[mockingly ]
!Oh, let's go jelly fishing"
：[嘲讽]
！哦，我们去钓果冻吧”
.We don't have any work to do"
.我们没有任何工作要做”
Life is just a big bowl"
of fancy, assorted cashews
人生就是一个大碗”
精美的什锦腰果
and nobody has anything"
to dust or to clean
没有人拥有任何东西”
除尘或清洁
"!or to wipe, or fabricate
“！或者擦拭，或者捏造
But, Patrick, the only thing
I've ever seen you clean
但是，帕特里克，唯一的事情
我见过你干净
.is your plate
.是你的盘子吗
[sobbing ]
[抽泣]
,I don't know what to do
.Spongebob
,我不知道该怎么办
.海绵宝宝
!You got to help me
！你必须帮助我
Patrick, you forgot
.how to eat again
帕特里克，你忘了
.如何再吃
Come on, we'll
.get the funnel
来吧，我们会
.获取漏斗
,No, it's not that
.Spongebob; it's worse
,不,不是那样的
.海绵宝宝；更糟了
Darn, I like
.the funnel
该死，我喜欢
.漏斗
?Well, what is it then
？那么，那是什么？
!Look
！看
.Hey, a note
.嘿，请注意
.Yeah, but turn it over
.是的，但是把它翻过来
.There's a letter
.有一封信
.You're right
。你说得对
And I got this message
.from my parents
我收到了这条消息
.来自我的父母
?Your parents
?你的父母
,Dear Patrick"
Your mom and I
亲爱的帕特里克”
你妈妈和我
are coming out tomorrow"
.for Starfish Day
明天就会出来”
.海星日
,Please try to remember"
but don't try too hard
，请试着记住”
但不要太努力
or you'll hurt yourself"
.like last time
否则你会伤害自己”
.像上次一样
".Love, Daddy
“.爱，爸爸
Spongebob, my parents think
I'm dumber
海绵宝宝，我父母认为
我比较笨
.than a sack of diapers
.比一袋尿布
,No, they don't
.Patrick
，不，他们不
.帕特里克
Parents just like
...to push your buttons
父母就像
...按下按钮
!like this-- Nee
!像这样-- Nee
[laughing ]
[笑]
.That always cheers me up
.这总是让我振作起来
.But not today
.但不是今天
Patrick, if your parents
think you're dumb
帕特里克，如果你的父母
认为你很蠢
then they must not know
.what dumb really is
那么他们一定不知道
.真正的愚蠢是什么
But don't they watch
?television
但他们不看吗
？电视
.That's what I'm saying, Pat
.这就是我要说的，帕特
If your parents got to meet
a real dummy
如果你的父母要见面
一个真正的假人
they'd realize what genius
.you really are
他们会意识到什么是天才
.你确实是
Oh, but don't genius live
?in a lamp
哦，但天才不存在
？在一盏灯里
And besides, we don't know
.any dumb people
除此之外，我们不知道
.任何愚蠢的人
.Don't worry, Patrick
.别担心，帕特里克
!I'll be the dummy
！我将成为假人
When your parents see
how dumb I act
当你父母看到
我表现得多么愚蠢
they'll think you're
.the smartest guy ever
他们会认为你是
.有史以来最聪明的人
!Math is power
！数学就是力量
A, B, C, D
A、B、C、D
[E, F, G...[ doorbell rings
[E、F、G...[门铃响了
...Oh! ...H, I, J, K, L, M, N, O
...哦！ ...H、I、J、K、L、M、N、O
Should I get the bullhorn
?again, Marty
我应该拿扩音器吗
？再次，马蒂
?W, X, Y and Z...
？W、X、Y 和 Z...
.Hi, Mom
.嗨，妈妈
.Hi, Dad
.嗨，爸爸
Son, you recognized us
.this time
儿子，你认出了我们
.这次
Why wouldn't I recognize
?my own parents
为什么我不认识
？我自己的父母
.You never were a bright one
.你从来都不是一个聪明的人
...Uh
...呃
[laughing ]
[笑]
Well, aren't you going
?to show us inside
嗯，你不去吗
？向我们展示里面
He probably forgot
.where it is
他大概忘记了
.它在哪里
...I know where
...我知道在哪里
Oh, let me lead the way
?so we don't get lost, huh
哦，让我带路吧
？这样我们就不会迷路了，哈
.Hold hands now
.现在牵手
.Okay, we're almost there
.好吧，我们快到了
.Let go on three
.放开三
.One, two, three
。一二三
!Good job
！好工作
.Pats for Patrick.Pats for Patrick
.拍拍帕特里克.拍拍帕特里克
[both laughing ]
[两人都笑了]
.I'll go get the beverages
.我去拿饮料
[ice cubes tinkling ]
[冰块叮当作响]
!Wow, son
！哇，儿子
You put the drinks insomething
.this time
你把饮料放进去
.这次
Aw, son, you must've been
working all night
哦，儿子，你一定是
通宵工作
to put these together
.for us
把这些放在一起
.对于我们来说
.We love you
.我们爱你
[groaning ]
[呻吟]
!doorbell rings]Hooray, the idiot's here ]
！门铃响了]万岁，白痴来了]
.I mean, I'll get it
.我的意思是，我会得到它
.Protective helmet-- check
.防护头盔--检查
[meows ]
[喵]
I'm supposed
.to look stupid, Gary
我应该
.看起来很愚蠢，加里
[meows ]
[喵]
?What could go wrong
？可能会出现什么问题
.What a surprise
.真是一个惊喜
.Hi
。你好
,Mom, Dad, meet my neighbor
.Spongebob
，爸爸妈妈，来见见我的邻居
.海绵宝宝
.Hi
。你好
.Hello there
。你好呀
?How do you do
？你好吗
.Hi
。你好
.Put her there
.把她放在那里
:[mechanical voice ]
!Mama, Mama
：[机械声音]
！妈妈，妈妈
.He means shake
.他的意思是摇动
!No, Spongebob, no
！不，海绵宝宝，不
.Shake hands
。握手
.No, Spongebob
.不，海绵宝宝
.Grab my dad's hand
.抓住我爸爸的手
Grab it with
.only one hand
抓住它
.只有一只手
!Good boy
！好孩子
Now move your
.arm up and down
现在移动你的
.手臂向上和向下
[giggling ]
[咯咯笑]
,So, Spongebob
?do you live nearby
,所以，海绵宝宝
？你住在附近吗
.Hi
。你好
.No, Spongebob
.Show them your house
.不，海绵宝宝
.向他们展示你的房子
,No, not your blouse
.your house
，不，不是你的衬衫
.你的房子
[screaming ]
[尖叫]
?He lives in a fruit
？他住在一个水果里
.That's unhealthy
.那是不健康的
[laughing ]
[笑]
!Hey, Spongebob
！嘿，海绵宝宝
You want to stay
?for dinner
你想留下来
？吃晚饭
[babbling ]
[胡言乱语]
[chuckles ]
[笑声]
Does he always do that
?after he eats
他总是这样做吗
？他吃完后
:PATRICK
.Only on Wednesday
：帕特里克
.仅限周三
[buzzing loudly ]
[大声嗡嗡声]
[chuckling ]
[轻笑]
Uh, Patrick, I think your friend
.might be broken
呃，帕特里克，我想你的朋友
.可能坏了
Yeah, and it would take
more than some masking tape
是的，这需要
不仅仅是一些遮蔽胶带
.to fix that guy
.修复那个人
[siren blares ]
[警笛声]
?Whoa! Is he going to be okay
？哇！他会没事吗
.Oh, that's nothing
.哦，那没什么
You should see him
in the morning
你应该见见他
早上
,prancing around, yelling
!Harmony! Harmony! Harmony"
、蹦蹦跳跳、大喊大叫
！和谐！和谐！和谐”
He drives
.all the neighbors crazy
他开车
.所有的邻居都疯了
Why, just the other day
...our neighbor Squidward was
为什么，就在前几天
[elephant trumpets ]
[大象喇叭]
[clattering ]
[咔哒声]
There's really
.no help for him
真的有
.对他没有帮助
I mean, look at
.the way he's dressed
我的意思是，看看
.他的穿着方式
Only somebody with holes
drilled in their head
只有一个有洞的人
钻在他们的脑袋里
.would wear that stuff
.会穿那个东西
?And how about this shape
？这个形状怎么样？
I mean, I've heard
of barrel-chested
我是说，我听说过
桶状胸的
!but never box-chested
！但绝不是箱型胸肌
[all laughing ]
[全都笑了]
Hey, Spongebob, do you have
?any mascara I could borrow
嘿，海绵宝宝，你有吗？
？我可以借用什么睫毛膏吗
[chuckles ]
[笑声]
?The boy wears makeup
？男孩化了妆
!What a card
！多么好的一张卡啊
[laughing ]
[笑]
[laughter continues ]
[笑声继续]
.Hey, Patrick
.嘿，帕特里克
!Patrick
！帕特里克
.Aw, he said my name
.哦，他说了我的名字
Wow, how'd you train
?him to do that
哇，你是怎么训练的
？他这样做
[laughter ]
[笑声]
.Ow! He bit me
.噢！他咬了我
,Patrick
.meet me in the kitchen
,帕特里克
.在厨房见我
Oh, I guess the dummy
wants to have a private
.conversation
哦，我猜是假人
想要拥有一个私人的
.对话
[laughing ]
[笑]
!A dumb one
！一个笨蛋
[laughing ]
[笑]
?So, what's on your mind
？所以，你在想什么
!No, wait
！不，等等
:I already know the answer
.nothing
: 我已经知道答案了
.没什么
[laughing ]
[笑]
,See, that's funny
!'cause you're dumb
，看，这很有趣
！因为你很蠢
Patrick, could you let up
on the insults
帕特里克，你能放手吗
关于侮辱
?just a little bit
？就一点点
Oh, we're those too complicated
?for you
哦，我们太复杂了
？为你
I'll try dumbingthem down
.a bit
我会尝试让他们变得愚蠢
.一点
Patrick, I get the feeling
.that you think I really am dumb
帕特里克，我有这种感觉
.你认为我真的很蠢
:[chuckling ]
That's just what I'd expect
.you to say
：[咯咯笑]
这正是我所期望的
.你说
Dumb people are always
blissfully unaware
愚蠢的人总是
幸福地不知道
.of how dumb they really are
.他们到底有多蠢
[moans ]
[呻吟]
.I'm only pretending to be dumb
.我只是装傻而已
?It was our plan, remember
？这是我们的计划，记住
Oh, Spongebob, if only
you could see
噢，海绵宝宝，要是这样就好了
你可以看到
how stupid you sound right now
你现在听起来多么愚蠢
with your talk
.of imaginary plans
用你的谈话
.想象中的计划
Tell you what, you've caught me
.in a good mood
告诉你，你抓住了我
.心情好
.I'll humor you
.我会逗你开心
Go on. Go out there and act
.smart for everyone
继续。走出去并采取行动
.适合所有人的智能
.Okay, I will
.好的，我会的
;And-and don't worry
.I'll keep this warm for you
;还有-别担心
.我会为你保暖
[clears throat ]
[清嗓子]
.I have a confession to make
.我有件事要坦白
.I lied about being stupid
.我谎称自己很蠢
I just acted like a fool
我只是表现得像个傻瓜
so you would appreciate Patrick
.a little bit more
所以你会感激帕特里克
.再多一点点
I know how to talk and eat
--and do laundry
我知道如何说话和吃饭
--然后洗衣服
I even separate the darks
.and the lights
我什至将黑暗分开
.和灯
So what do you say we start over
.and try again
那你说我们重新开始怎么样
.然后再试一次
Hi. My name is
Spongebob Squarepants
你好。我的名字是
海绵宝宝
.and I am not a dummy
.而且我不是假人
[chuckling ]
[轻笑]
Amazing. Three minutes
in the kitchen
惊人的。三分钟
在厨房里
and our son has taught him
.to talk in complete sentences
我们的儿子教了他
.用完整的句子说话
.Oh, good work, son
.哦，干得好，儿子
.It wasn't easy, Dad
.这并不容易，爸爸
:[stuttering ]
...B-but-but
：[结巴]
...B-但是-但是
It looks like it's time
.for your next lesson, young man
看来是时候了
.年轻人，下节课
!Now listen to me
!I'm not dumb
！现在听我说
！我不傻
.I have a brain
.See, here's a picture of it
.我有脑子
.看，这是它的图片
.That must be actual size
.那一定是实际尺寸
[laughter ]
[笑声]
No! It's normal size
.and fully functional
不！这是正常尺寸
.并且功能齐全
.Watch
。手表
.Two plus two equals four
.二加二等于四
,Oh, son, you taught him math
.too
哦，儿子，你教他数学
.太
!No
！不
.Andyou taught him to sing
.Andyou教他唱歌
[babbling ]
[胡言乱语]
Oh, now he's
.short-circuiting
哦，现在他是
.短路
You must've taught him
.a little too much
一定是你教过他的
.有点太多了
[laughing ]
[笑]
[laughter continues ]
[笑声继续]
[laughter continuing ]
[screaming ]
[尖叫]
You know, son
你知道，儿子
I've always known
that when it comes to brightness
我一直都知道
当谈到亮度时
.well, you're about a three-watt
.嗯，你的功率大约是三瓦
But this guy... he's a wet match
.in a dark cave
但这家伙...他是个湿手
.在一个黑暗的洞穴里
He makes
.phone operators seem smart
他让
.电话运营商看起来很聪明
[clears throat ]
But more importantly, son
[清嗓子]
但更重要的是儿子
,he's shown me what a sharp
.quick-witted boy you've become
，他向我展示了多么敏锐
.你已经成为一个机智的男孩
I-I feel like I'm
really meeting you
.for the first time
我-我感觉我是
真的遇见你
.第一次
?Isn't that right, Janet
？不是吗，珍妮特
.You bet, Marty
.你打赌，马蒂
?Janet
？珍妮特
!?Marty
！？马蒂
!?Who are you people
！？你们是谁？
.Marty, I'm scared
.马蒂，我很害怕
[doorbell rings ]
[门铃响了]
.Excuse me
。打扰一下
Does this lovely
?couple belong to you
这可爱吗
?情侣属于你
They've been standing
outside my house saying
他们一直站着
在我家外面说
.Where's Patrick?" all day"
.帕特里克在哪里？“一整天”
!It's driving me nuts
！这让我发疯
!Mom! Dad
！妈妈！爸爸
Wow, son, you actually
.recognized us this time
哇，儿子，你真的
.这次认出了我们
And you remembered
.to get dressed today
而你还记得
.今天穿衣服
[all laughing ]
[全都笑了]
,Oh, that's right, honey
.we don't have a son
，哦，原来如此，亲爱的
.我们没有儿子
.Oh, yeah
.哦，是的
[laughter continuing ]
[笑声继续]
Captioning sponsored by THE]
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
字幕由 THE 赞助]
美国教育部
and NICKELODEON
和尼克国际儿童频道
Captioned by
The Caption Center
[WGBH Educational Foundation
标题为
字幕中心
[WGBH 教育基金会
标题为
字幕中心
[WGBH 教育基金会